<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description>I am Ritchie Ng, a machine learning engineer specializing in deep learning and computer vision. Check out my code guides and keep ritching for the skies!</description>
        <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://www.ritchieng.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 20:57:16 -0400</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 20:57:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>Comic Series: The Future of Labelled Data</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Weirdly, there is something similar offered by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scaleapi.com&quot;&gt;Scale&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://67.media.tumblr.com/c5b10a31b2b4e7166765fc1aaa7b3afa/tumblr_of1vvyIlU41vf3ktto1_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/labels</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/labels</guid>
            
            <category>comic_series</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Comic Series: Support Vector Machines</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Support Vector Machines are often called Largest Margin Classifier.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/f812e7d53d4ee4a75bae2fdfd8125257/tumblr_oekxc5CLuc1vf3ktto1_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/svms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/svms</guid>
            
            <category>comic_series</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Comic Series: Convolutional Neural Nets</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As a disclaimer, Derpina intentionally set the output to two classes: “pretty girl” or “not so pretty girl”. We do not know if she intentionally manipulated the labels that led to her findings.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://67.media.tumblr.com/184bf6df1de46292400acdd00b833585/tumblr_odzjaoOxt91vf3ktto1_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/convnet-derpina/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/convnet-derpina/</guid>
            
            <category>comic_series</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Comic Series: Markov Decision Processes with High Rewards</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine yourself in a grid-like world with two end goals (absorbing states), what would you do? Would you reach for the drumstick or drop into the hole? 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://67.media.tumblr.com/fd42817dab067cab16d3fb5b9e4287a0/tumblr_odmi9cp6cH1vf3ktto1_r1_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/mdp-high-rewards/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/comic-series/mdp-high-rewards/</guid>
            
            <category>comic_series</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Completed Data School&#39;s Pandas Q&amp;A Series</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;pandas-series-by-data-school&quot;&gt;Pandas Series by Data School&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a free course offered by Data School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/easier-data-analysis-with-pandas/&quot;&gt;Introduction to Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not like reading books or guides, this is a very good series. You might think it’s simply a series of videos but it covers a lot of essential parts of pandas that allow you to have an adequate knowledge to work with scikit-learn and actual data sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I cannot emphasise how Mark has a way to deliver simple and succinct explanations on complicated topics. This is very important for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/pandas-introduction/&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that I have derived from the course useful! They are some variations on Github by others so feel free to use them too if you feel their explanations are clearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be moving on to Udacity’s Machine Learning nanodegree along with other online resources where I will document my progress. You can view my personal list on how to be a Machine Learning Engineer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-resources/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best, Ritchie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-pandas-qna-data-school/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-pandas-qna-data-school/</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            <category>becoming_a_machine_learning_engineer</category>
            
            <category>pandas</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Completed Data School&#39;s free Machine Learning tutorials</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;machine-learning-with-scikit-learn-with-data-school&quot;&gt;Machine Learning with scikit-learn with Data School&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a free course offered by Data School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning with scikit-learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/easier-data-analysis-with-pandas/&quot;&gt;Introduction to Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is good for people who have completed Andrew Ng’s class on Machine Learning. You would start to realise how scikit-learn automates a lot of the low-level Octave code you implemented in Andrew Ng’s class from the simple gradient descent algorithm, to regularization, and the mind-boggling neural networks. Although I will be writing more on Neural Networks using Tensorflow (formerly known as Skflow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the tutorials offered by Data School are good for people who are new to scikit-learn and Python in general. If you do not want to watch his free open-source videos, you can check out my notes on all his tutorials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-intro-easy/&quot;&gt;Introduction to Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/ipython-introduction/&quot;&gt;IPython Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-iris-dataset/&quot;&gt;Exploring Iris Dataset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-k-nearest-neighbors-knn/&quot;&gt;KNN Classification Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-linear-regression/&quot;&gt;Linear Regression Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-cross-validation/&quot;&gt;Cross-validation for Parameter Tuning, Model Selection and Feature Selection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-efficiently-search-tuning-param/&quot;&gt;Efficiently Searching Optimal Tuning Parameters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-evaluate-classification-model/&quot;&gt;Evaluating a Classification Model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you found my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-intro-easy/&quot;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; useful! They are some variations on Github by others so feel free to use them too if you feel their explanations are clearer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be moving on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/easier-data-analysis-with-pandas/&quot;&gt;Pandas Series by Data School&lt;/a&gt;. Pandas plays an important role in data wrangling. Check out my review on this series soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-machine-learning-data-school-start/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-machine-learning-data-school-start/</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            <category>becoming_a_machine_learning_engineer</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Completed Machine Learning by Andrew Ng, Stanford University!</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;machine-learning-by-andrew-ng&quot;&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I completed the course and I have documented my notes under &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4005/machine-learning/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, you can check out my full Github repository &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ritchieng&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course teaches you the theoretical foundations of Machine Learning and allows you to apply the theory you learn using Octave (Matlab). I had my doubts about Octave. But because of the simplicity of it, it is indeed a very good choice over many other programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course began and the workload and content were manageable. But halfway through, I almost died.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most challenging part of this course is on Neural Networks. The mathematical theory and implementation in code are both very challenging, at least to me. The other parts of the course are much easier than the Neural Networks’ weeks. So do not give up when you are undergoing the weeks teaching Neural Networks. Keep perservering and you will make it through. You can seek help from “Discussions” and with some guides on the tutorials given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learnt a lot from this course and I could finally understand all the articles I read online and go through the famous scikit-learn documentation understanding many of the algorithms that have been nicely implemented and you can use them with a few lines of codes compared to implementing them from the bottom-up using Octave (Matlab), R, Java, Python, C++ or any other programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe I found a good accompanying course for this course offered by Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) in case you want to cover topics that were not covered by Andrew Ng or delve into the topics he covered from a different perspective. You can access the course &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~tom/10701_sp11/lectures.shtml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; from CMU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I am going to complete Data School’s introduction to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/machine-learning-with-scikit-learn/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; using scikit-learn and their guide on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataschool.io/easier-data-analysis-with-pandas/&quot;&gt;Pandas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And from late August, I will be embarking on Udacity’s Machine Learning nanodegree programme where I will offer my detailed review!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-machine-learning-andrew-ng-stanford/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/completed-machine-learning-andrew-ng-stanford/</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            <category>becoming_a_machine_learning_engineer</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Machine Learning by Andrew Ng, Stanford University</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;machine-learning-by-andrew-ng&quot;&gt;Machine Learning by Andrew Ng&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just started this course and I have documented my notes under &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1:4005/machine-learning/&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;. I made it to the end of week 3 in 7 days while committing a few hours everyday. Rather slow but I am currently travelling now with commitments so I have to make do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intend to complete this course in another 6 more days. Sure I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notes-and-scripts&quot;&gt;Notes and scripts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, you can check out my full Github repository &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ritchieng&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-the-beginning/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/machine-learning-the-beginning/</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            <category>becoming_a_machine_learning_engineer</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Beginning</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;who-am-i&quot;&gt;Who am I?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a year and a half majoring in finance in Business School, National University of Singapore, I will be completing my final semester as a business student after I am back in early 2017 and moving on to my postgraduate experience in Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy expanding my knowledge in econometrics. I enjoyed my time restructuring debts and raising money in my first year in NUS. But I enjoy being a newbie software developer even more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started a few start-ups since I was 12. Some failed, some succeeded. In search of the big one, I just kept swimming. Remember Dory in Finding Nemo? “Just keep swimming. Just keep swimming. Just keep swimming, swimming, swimming. What do we do? We swim, swim.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is to let anyone out there know that regardless of what you are studying or currently working as, you can do anything. In fact, I think the combination of BBA, MPP and programming is a weird combination. Just do it. It is going to be a colossal challenge. But what is life without a challenge?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-purpose-of-this-website&quot;&gt;What is the purpose of this website?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is to document all my notes and guides that I have created and will create in the near future in the areas of Machine Learning, Data Science and Algorithmic Trading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I built this website using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jekyll and Github Pages. It is proudly hosted for free using Github Pages. It is challenging to serve this website entirely using static pages, but I managed to figure a way out and this documentation-style website is nearly perfect for my intention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will feature these favourite programming languages on top of the three major areas:
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Python&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Octave&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Java&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Javascript&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;HTML5&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CSS3&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meteor&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ReactJS&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SCSS&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
And so I begin…&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/welcome-ritchieng/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/welcome-ritchieng/</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>becoming_a_machine_learning_engineer</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
