<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description>I am Ritchie Ng, a machine learning engineer specializing in deep learning and computer vision. Check out my code guides and keep ritching for the skies!</description>
        <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://www.ritchieng.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:07:56 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 09:07:56 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>IT Youth of the Year Award</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1552267733/award_it_youth_2019_rwzanm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very happy to be the IT Youth Leader of the Year 2019 in Singapore for my industry and non-profit contribution in AI at ensemblecap.ai, NUS, Deep Learning Wizard and NVIDIA!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would like to thank the professor who changed my life, believed in me and nominated me for consideration, Professor Chua Tat-Seng from NExT Centre, NUS School of Computing. Big thanks to everyone who helped for this in NExT Centre particularly Choon Meng, Tek Min, Chua Yi Hao, and Eugene Tan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to an important friend and associate who stuck by with me all the way, Jie Fu from our endless days of programming (and scribbling equations) during your PhD years to now as a postdoc in MILA 🙂And Ilija Ilievski from those years till now too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big thanks to the people who believed in the future of AI and asset management and made this happen with the original team Damien Loh, Atsuo Ogaki, and Samuel Chen from ensemblecap.ai&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to new found close friend Alfredo Canziani who motivated me on open-source education further and supporting each other 🙂 And thanks to Moustapha Cisse for setting up an amazing initiative in Africa with #AMMI to kickstart a future of AI by Africa and trusted your students with our teaching. And I’m on my starting journey to help as many students of your as possible by guiding them on learning like Merghaney Mohammed and Enoch Tetteh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Soumith Chintala for spearheading #PyTorch and it’s now in production running critical functions in finance (like my firm) and tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Marek Bardoński where our friendship started when you were in #NVIDIA and we’ve supported each other ever since in our learning journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to #NVIDIA for allowing me to lead deep learning workshops under DLI in NUS all these years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my mentors and everyone in #PhilipYeoInitiative like Abel Ang, Seok Lin Khoo, Kiren Kumar, Claire Cheong, Chong Siak Ching, and Kai Hoe Tan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last thanks to everyone in #SingaporeComputerSociety like Jason Chen for being there when I was nervous and Howie Lau for spearheading tech from start till now. And to a senior big award winner I’ve a lot to learn and also from NUS: Jeffrey Tiong!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to forward-looking civil servants and minister like Minister S Iswaran for gracing the event and delivering a speech on digital readiness and skills empowerment for Singaporeans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my family for being by my side Carine Chng, Ng William, and Adabelle Ng for giving me the freedom and support to pursue whatever I wanted even from young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the future of AI!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/awards/it-youth-of-the-year-2019</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/awards/it-youth-of-the-year-2019</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>To the future of AI in and beyond Africa</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1542700156/ritchieng.com/ammi_facebook_google_2018/ammi_students_2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helped to teach these students from The African Masters of Machine Intelligence (AMMI) by The African Institute for Mathematical Sciences (AIMS) with Alfredo Canziani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A unique pedagogy is required for deep learning beginning with intuition, culminating in just enough math, and ending with programming. This approached has worked when I delivered my deep learning course to over 3000 students over 120 countries. And I continue to champion this pedagogy. I’m very pleased that I share the same passion with Alfedo when he delivered his interactive lectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importantly, I see great potential when I personally interacted with students here. I see future deep learning researchers and applied machine intelligence experts who have the potential to make groundbreaking changes in the fields of healthcare, agriculture and education throughout Africa. With the right education, mentorship and opportunities, they would be pioneers. Simply put, deep learning talent is underexplored in this continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thankful to Alfredo Canziani who has been my best pal and inspirational guy while I was there, Moustapha Cisse for creating these opportunities for young African students to thrive, #Facebook and #Google for supporting this program, and Pedro Antonio Martínez Mediano and Marc Deisenroff. Coincidentally, I would also like to thank Yoshua Bengio for holding ICLR in Africa in 2020 for the first time that he announced recently. Finally, really appreciate how #PyTorch has made programming neural networks more approachable and it was made possible with the amazing PyTorch community sparked by Soumith Chintala.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking about community, I got to contribute to the deep learning community with the help from supportive groups and individuals from the global deep learning community. Likewise, we should continually help these young Africans like any other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the future of AI in and beyond Africa. Looking forward to help Moustapha in any way I can to nurture AI talent 🙂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m being a fanboy here, but Yann Lecun liked my post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ritchiengz/posts/2267714723302661&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/community/ammi-aims-facebook-google</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/community/ammi-aims-facebook-google</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Recap of 2018 NExT++ AI Workshop</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nextcenter.org/event/next-workshop-2018-nanjing/&quot;&gt;NExT++’s 3rd Workshop&lt;/a&gt; and this time we are looking at the applications and development of AI related technologies in the healthcare and finance verticals with the theme “AI in Health and Finance”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual summary of my talk on AI and Unstructured Analytics in Fintech. Doesn’t contain everything, but whatever the non-technical designers could come up with in real-time. Really amazing so kudos to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really thankful to the whole team in my former lab, NExT++ and a close friend, Choon Meng, for making all the arrangements. Also thanks to Tek Min, Yi Hao and everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Super happy to catch up with Prof Tat-Seng Chua (KITHCT Chair Professor at the School of Computing), Prof Sun Maosong (Dean of Department of Computer Science and Technology, Tsinghua University), and Prof Dame Wendy Hall (Director of the Web Science Institute, University of Southampton).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1541237753/ritchieng.com/ritchieng_talk_nanjing_next_2018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/conferences/next++-nanjing--2018</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/conferences/next++-nanjing--2018</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Recap of 2018 PyTorch Developer Conference</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Proud of how far PyTorch has come. Thanks Soumith Chintala, it is a great journey and it just started. And thanks to Adam Paszke too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally got to catch up with Soumith Chintala, Alfredo Canziani and Marek Bardoński and found Andrej Karpathy! Back to Singapore tonight 🤗&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some photos of my trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1538729876/ritchieng.com/pytorch_devcon_2018/IMG_2078_02-10-2018-21-00-43.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Soumith Chintala&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1538729876/ritchieng.com/pytorch_devcon_2018/IMG_2081_02-10-2018-21-00-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alfredo Canziani&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1538729876/ritchieng.com/pytorch_devcon_2018/IMG_2075_02-10-2018-21-02-31.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Andrej Karpathy&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/pytorch/pytorch-devcon-2018</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/pytorch/pytorch-devcon-2018</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>NVIDIA Image Classification at NUS-NUHS-MIT Datathon</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I held NVIDIA’s third deep learning workshop in NUS this year at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nus-datathon.com/workshop&quot;&gt;NUS-NUHS-MIT-Datathon&lt;/a&gt;! It’s amazing to see how deep learning is gaining traction in healthcare in Singapore. Fast forward 10 years and I see doctors working closely with deep learning algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to fellow people delivering the other 3 workshops: Prof Leo Celi (MIT) &amp;amp; Data Scientist team (MIT), Asst Prof Mengling ‘Mornin’ Feng (NUS), Dr Jason Pitt (CSI, NUS), and Dr Ngiam Kee Yuan (CTO, NUHS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-sit4-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/36656138_185674162103060_5268631017589047296_n.jpg?_nc_cat=0&amp;amp;oh=ecbc26fda2692387f409be42214174e3&amp;amp;oe=5BA2E57A&quot; alt=&quot;NVIDIA Workshop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-nuhs-mit-nus-datathon</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-nuhs-mit-nus-datathon</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>NVIDIA Object Detection with DIGITS 2018</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I am holding NVIDIA’s second deep learning workshop in NUS after popular demand for the first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many problems have established deep learning solutions, but sometimes the problem that you want to solve does not. Learn to create custom solutions through the challenge of detecting whale faces from aerial images by:
- Combining traditional computer vision with deep learning
- Performing minor “brain surgery” on an existing neural network using the deep learning framework Caffe
- Harnessing the knowledge of the deep learning community by identifying and using a purpose built network and end-to-end labeled data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to sign up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/nus.nvidia/posts/166945523975924&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1538729603/ritchieng.com/nus_nvidia/nus_nvidia_dli_2018_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NVIDIA Poster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop-2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop-2</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>NVIDIA Image Classification with DIGITS 2018</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As you know, I held NUS’ first NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute Workshop. Feel free to follow our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/nus.nvidia/&quot;&gt;NUS NVIDIA Facebook&lt;/a&gt; page for more workshops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this half-day Image Classification with DIGITS workshop, participants learnt to
- leverage deep neural networks (DNN) within the deep learning workflow to solve a real-world image classification problem using NVIDIA DIGITS.
- walk through the process of data preparation, model definition, model training and troubleshooting
- use validation data to test and try different strategies for improving model performance using GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a full house!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop-postmort</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop-postmort</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>NVIDIA Deep Learning Workshop 2018</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I am holding NVIDIA’s first deep learning workshop in NUS :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this half-day Image Classification with DIGITS workshop, you will learn to
- leverage deep neural networks (DNN) within the deep learning workflow to solve a real-world image classification problem using NVIDIA DIGITS.
- walk through the process of data preparation, model definition, model training and troubleshooting
- use validation data to test and try different strategies for improving model performance using GPUs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to sign up &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.sg/e/teaching-you-to-solve-problems-with-deep-learning-by-nvidia-tickets-45464548689&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/ritchieng/image/upload/v1538729603/ritchieng.com/nus_nvidia/nus_nvidia_dli_2018_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NVIDIA Poster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/nvidia-dli-deep-learning-workshop</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>I am an NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute Instructor!</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;As you know that through my website and my deep learning courses (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.deeplearningwizard.com/&quot;&gt;Deep Learning Wizard&lt;/a&gt;), I have been vigorously pushing for making deep learning more accessible to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I am thankful to announce that NVIDIA has given me the opportunity to be an NVIDIA Deep Learning Institute (DLI) instructor and ambassador in NUS to enable everyone to solve the most challenging problems in deep learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers,
&lt;br /&gt;Ritchie&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/ritchie-dli-instructor</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/nvidia-dli/ritchie-dli-instructor</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Practical Deep Learning with PyTorch</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;I have launched a course on deep learning with PyTorch that gets you starting with the PyTorch framework as well as understanding the transition from PyTorch fundamentals all the way to more complicated deep learning models. Sign up here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udemy.com/practical-deep-learning-with-pytorch/?couponCode=DEEPWIZARD&quot;&gt;https://www.udemy.com/practical-deep-learning-with-pytorch/?couponCode=DEEPWIZARD&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course is specifically designed such that if you are interested in diving deeper into the concepts and mathematics, you would be able to transition gradually with our upcoming courses in a series specializing in deep learning with PyTorch. It is also designed for anyone who wants to learn deep learning or are familiar with other frameworks and wish to use a framework that puts Python first.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <link>http://www.ritchieng.com/courses/practical-deep-learning-with-PyTorch</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ritchieng.com/courses/practical-deep-learning-with-PyTorch</guid>
            
            <category>news</category>
            
            <category>machine_learning</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
